<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Datacenter Journey on Datacenter Journey</title>
    <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Datacenter Journey on Datacenter Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 05:06:05 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://datacenterjourney.com/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>ESXi USB Installer - Manual</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/esxi-usb-installer-manual/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 05:06:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/esxi-usb-installer-manual/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Recently I came across the need to install hundreds of ESXi hosts on USB sticks and wanted to accomplish this in the easiest way possible. While installing ESXi isn&amp;rsquo;t complicated, it can be time-consuming and would require the need to be swapping the monitor and keyboard continually or having multiple monitors and keyboards. I wanted an unattended install method where I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to continue to touch each machine and have to go back configure it. I was not only able to accomplish this task, but also have the installer install ESXi on itself to minimize the number of USB drives needed. The plan was to start the install, walk away, and then come back to it after the installation was complete. Below are the steps I used on MacOS to be able to accomplish this task. Look for my next post where I script the USB creation process to make it even easier and faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are the manual steps to accomplish this using MacOS broken down into two different parts:
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;creating-bootable-usb-esxi-installer-on-mac-to-install-on-itself&#34;&gt;Creating bootable USB ESXi Installer on Mac to install on itself&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mount the required ESXi installer ISO by double-clicking it or running the command in Terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;hdiutil mount /path/to/ESXi.iso 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Insert the USB flash drive where you want ESXi installed and start up &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disk Utility&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select the USB flash drive so that we can erase it and format it with the following options:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Format: &lt;strong&gt;MS-DOS (FAT)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scheme: &lt;strong&gt;Master Boot Record&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Name: (example) &lt;strong&gt;ESXI-6-7-U2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After erasing the drive, we need to mark the partition as &lt;em&gt;active&lt;/em&gt;. Disk Utility does not support marking partitions as active so we need to use Terminal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;List all the mounted volumes to determine the identifier for the USB flash drive you inserted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;diskutil list
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Locate the disk identifier which should be something similar to &lt;em&gt;/dev/disk3s1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now to unmount the USB flash drive, note this is not the same as eject. Make sure to replace &lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Y&lt;/em&gt; with the proper numbers obtained from the previous command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;diskutil unmount /dev/diskXsY
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start up the command-line partitioner &lt;em&gt;fdisk&lt;/em&gt; in interactive mode which will require administrator privileges on the drive you identified in the previous commands:
&lt;code&gt;bash
sudo fdisk -e /dev/diskXsY
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once in fdisk, you flag the first partition on the volume as active and bootable:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;f 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, you write the changes:
&lt;code&gt;bash
write
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, you exit fdisk interactive mode:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;quit
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now to remount the USB flash drive using the diskutil command:
&lt;code&gt;bash
disktuil mount /dev/diskXsY
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now you will list the volumes of the mounted ESXi installer ISO and the USB flash drive you just formatted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;ls /Volumes/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy the entire contents of the ESXi ISO to the root of the USB flash drive either through Finder or terminal using the the command below:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;bash
cp -R /Volumes/ESXI-6.7.0-20190504001-STANDARD/* /ESXI-6-7-U2/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the USB flash drive rename the file ISOLINUX.CFG to SYSLINUX.CFG:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;mv /Volumes/ESXI-6-7-U2/ISOLINUX.CFG /Volumes/ESXI-6-7-U2/SYSLINUX.CFG
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now in order to have the flash drive boot automatically to the kickstart file that will be placed on the root of the install USB flash drive we need to edit the two BOOT.CFG files in the following locations using vi or nano:
&lt;code&gt;bash
vi /Volumes/ESXI-6-7-U2/BOOT.CFG
nano /Volumes/ESXI-6-7-U2/EFI/BOOT/BOOT.CFG
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find the line that starts with &lt;em&gt;kernelopt&lt;/em&gt; and delete everything after the equal sign. Then we will add the information in bold below to state that we want to load a kickstart script and list the location and name of the file:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;kernelopt=&lt;strong&gt;ks=usb:/ks.cfg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;editing-the-kickstart-file-to-configure-the-esxi-host&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editing the kickstart file to configure the ESXi host:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download the attached &lt;strong&gt;ks.cfg&lt;/strong&gt; file from my GitHub account to use and edit:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/datacenterjourney/kickstart_files/blob/master/ks.cfg&#34; title=&#34;download ks.cfg file&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ks.cfg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using a text editor (not Word) you will need to edit lines 12, 21, 30, 31, 40, and 43&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line 12 you will set the &amp;lsquo;root&amp;rsquo; password by replacing &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;{PASSWD}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line 21 you will change the information after the equal sign of the following &lt;strong&gt;device=&lt;em&gt;{NIC1}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;hostname=&lt;em&gt;{HOSTNAME}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;vlanid=&lt;em&gt;{VLANID}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;ip=&lt;em&gt;{IPADDR}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;netmask=&lt;em&gt;{SUBNET}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;gateway=&lt;em&gt;{GATEWAY}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;nameserver=&lt;em&gt;{DNS1},{DNS2}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line 30 you will set IP or hostname of the NTP server replacing &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;{NTP1}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line 31 if you have a second NTP IP or hostname you will replace &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;{NTP2}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have or want to use a second NTP server then you can comment out the line by placing a &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;#&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; at the beginning of the line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line 40 you will again replace &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;{HOSTNAME}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; with the same name you used in line 21.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line 43 you will replace the information after the equal sign &lt;strong&gt;uplink-name=&lt;em&gt;{NIC2}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; if you want to set a second management nic. If you only have one nic or don&amp;rsquo;t want assign a second network adater then you can comment out the line by placing a &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;#&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; at the beginning of the line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save the file and then copy to the root of the USB flash drive you created as the install drive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You now have a fully configured unattended USB ESXi installation drive. All that is left to do is plug in the USB drive to the hardware you want to configure and power it on. I hope this helps you and ultimately saves you time when having to install ESXi on multiple hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey Start</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/journeystart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 17:14:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/journeystart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To give you a little bit of background on me and how I got started in my IT  career back in 2002. As a recent college graduate with little to no experience and only armed with a bachelor degree in Management Information Systems, I thought the job offers were going to be plentiful for me to choose from just by applying. Little did I know that it was not as easy as listing the fact that I had a piece a paper showing that I could learn and pass tests. After just a few months of job searching, I was made aware of an essential skill that I would need if I were to progress. It was the fact that to get anywhere in my future career that I would have to start networking and building relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine who worked at the Fremont Hotel &amp;amp; Casino, as a banquet supervisor, reached out to me letting me know that he wanted to introduce me to someone who might be able to help me get into an IT position. The person he had me meet with was the cage cashier manager. I thought to myself, how is she going to help get me into IT??? Not having any success on my own trying to land a job I decided to meet with her and hear what she had to tell me. It turns out that she had become good friends with the manager of the helpdesk for Boyd Gaming. What she was offering me was a position to work for her in the cage, and after six months, she would help me apply for a transfer to the corporate helpdesk. The catch was that there was no guarantee as to when or if there would be an open position once I was eligible, and she would be taking note of my work ethic and personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to take a chance on the offer and start my position as a cage cashier. It couldn&amp;rsquo;t be harder than my current job, which was working at my dad&amp;rsquo;s company doing masonry work.  I kept a constant eye on the internal job postings, and after just eight months as a cashier, there was an opening at the helpdesk. True to her word, the cage manager helped me apply for the transfer and gave a great reference based on my work ethic and personality. I was scheduled for an interview during which I was able to convey to Theresa, the helpdesk manager, that I would be a good fit for the position. She felt confident enough that I would be able to do well in the role and decided to hire me and be able to prove her right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lessons learned here are something that I feel cannot be stressed enough. First, take the time to make and grow your personal and professional network of contacts because you never know when they might be able to help you out. However, don&amp;rsquo;t build these relationships for the sole purpose of trying to get ahead. Next, always work hard no matter what the task at hand. People will take notice of your work ethic, and it goes a long way towards building your reputation. Lastly, there will be times when you feel like nothing is going in your favor. Be persistent and never give up. I believe that life like baseball is a game of failure. Most of the time, things won&amp;rsquo;t go your way just because you want them to. It&amp;rsquo;s how you handle those failures and learn from them that will help you grow as a person and a professional.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Welcome, my name is Manuel Martinez, and I&amp;rsquo;m from Las Vegas, NV. I have been in the IT field since graduating from college back in 2002. I have worked my way up the ranks through the many positions I have held in different industries. This site is a collection of stories, notes, and information that I have gathered along the way that I hope helps others in the community along their journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of my site is to get to learn a little about me, my career and tips I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered along the way about all things data center. I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing stories about the different roles that I have held, the skills I learned along the way, and how I used them to be able to evolve in my career. There are tips about how I learned those new skills and have used them in my past and current jobs, and some of the new skills I&amp;rsquo;ve acquired or am in the process of learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While most of my focus is around VMware and it&amp;rsquo;s products, I also enjoy working with Cisco UCS and PowerShell. Those products have led me towards other technologies in the Software Defined Data Center and around automation. There is a combination of technical deep dives around products I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with, high-level summaries about technologies I&amp;rsquo;m learning about, and reference material for others to use for learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that you find the material here entertaining, informative, or helpful and look forward to sharing my data center journey with you and having you join me for the rest of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The views and opinions expressed here are my own and do not reflect the views of any of my past or current employers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
