<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Datacenter Journey on Datacenter Journey</title>
    <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Datacenter Journey on Datacenter Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 17:14:24 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://datacenterjourney.com/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey Start</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/journeystart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 17:14:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/journeystart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To give you a little bit of background on me and how I got started in my IT  career back in 2002. As a recent college graduate with little to no experience and only armed with a bachelor degree in Management Information Systems, I thought the job offers were going to be plentiful for me to choose from just by applying. Little did I know that it was not as easy as listing the fact that I had a piece a paper showing that I could learn and pass tests. After just a few months of job searching, I was made aware of an essential skill that I would need if I were to progress. It was the fact that to get anywhere in my future career that I would have to start networking and building relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine who worked at the Fremont Hotel &amp;amp; Casino, as a banquet supervisor, reached out to me letting me know that he wanted to introduce me to someone who might be able to help me get into an IT position. The person he had me meet with was the cage cashier manager. I thought to myself, how is she going to help get me into IT??? Not having any success on my own trying to land a job I decided to meet with her and hear what she had to tell me. It turns out that she had become good friends with the manager of the helpdesk for Boyd Gaming. What she was offering me was a position to work for her in the cage, and after six months, she would help me apply for a transfer to the corporate helpdesk. The catch was that there was no guarantee as to when or if there would be an open position once I was eligible, and she would be taking note of my work ethic and personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to take a chance on the offer and start my position as a cage cashier. It couldn&amp;rsquo;t be harder than my current job, which was working at my dad&amp;rsquo;s company doing masonry work.  I kept a constant eye on the internal job postings, and after just eight months as a cashier, there was an opening at the helpdesk. True to her word, the cage manager helped me apply for the transfer and gave a great reference based on my work ethic and personality. I was scheduled for an interview during which I was able to convey to Theresa, the helpdesk manager, that I would be a good fit for the position. She felt confident enough that I would be able to do well in the role and decided to hire me and be able to prove her right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lessons learned here are something that I feel cannot be stressed enough. First, take the time to make and grow your personal and professional network of contacts because you never know when they might be able to help you out. However, don&amp;rsquo;t build these relationships for the sole purpose of trying to get ahead. Next, always work hard no matter what the task at hand. People will take notice of your work ethic, and it goes a long way towards building your reputation. Lastly, there will be times when you feel like nothing is going in your favor. Be persistent and never give up. I believe that life like baseball is a game of failure. Most of the time, things won&amp;rsquo;t go your way just because you want them to. It&amp;rsquo;s how you handle those failures and learn from them that will help you grow as a person and a professional.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Placeholder</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/placeholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 22:34:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/placeholder/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;temporary-post&#34;&gt;Temporary Post&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just a placeholder post until I complete writing my first actual post so stay tuned&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Welcome, my name is Manuel Martinez, and I&amp;rsquo;m from Las Vegas, NV. I have been in the IT field since graduating from college back in 2002. I have worked my way up the ranks through the many positions I have held in different industries. This site is a collection of stories, notes, and information that I have gathered along the way that I hope helps others in the community along their journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of my site is to get to learn a little about me, my career and tips I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered along the way about all things data center. I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing stories about the different roles that I have held, the skills I learned along the way, and how I used them to be able to evolve in my career. There are tips about how I learned those new skills and have used them in my past and current jobs, and some of the new skills I&amp;rsquo;ve acquired or am in the process of learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While most of my focus is around VMware and it&amp;rsquo;s products, I also enjoy working with Cisco UCS and PowerShell. Those products have led me towards other technologies in the Software Defined Data Center and around automation. There is a combination of technical deep dives around products I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with, high-level summaries about technologies I&amp;rsquo;m learning about, and reference material for others to use for learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that you find the material here entertaining, informative, or helpful and look forward to sharing my data center journey with you and having you join me for the rest of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The views and opinions expressed here are my own and do not reflect the views of any of my past or current employers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
