<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>macOS on Datacenter Journey</title>
    <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/categories/macos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in macOS on Datacenter Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 20:06:43 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://datacenterjourney.com/categories/macos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Install VCSA Certificates MacOS</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2020/install-vcsa-certificates-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 20:06:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2020/install-vcsa-certificates-macos/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve all come across the pesky invalid certificate error when trying to access vCenter, stating that your connection is not private. Many of us click through and &amp;ldquo;Accept the risk&amp;rdquo; because we know that the site we are accessing is legitimate. However, there are times where not having a trusted website can cause an issue and prevent specific actions. For example, without a trusted certificate, it blocks access to upload files to datastores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change MacOS Screenshot Defaults</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2020/change-macos-screenshot-defaults/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 13:55:10 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2020/change-macos-screenshot-defaults/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking lots of screenshots lately for blog posts and find myself constantly updating the files and locations. I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of having to repeatedly rename multiple files or move them into the appropriate folder locations to keep them organized. The process is time-consuming, and since I don&amp;rsquo;t always write the blog post after performing the actions, it can lead to confusion. I did some searching and found that it&amp;rsquo;s straightforward to change the default location and name of screenshot files take with a Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send F11 Key on macOS</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/send_f11_on_macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 19:51:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/send_f11_on_macos/</guid>
      <description>I enjoy using a Mac both for work and at home. There is an issue that I have come upon more than one occasion, and it always takes me a while to remember how to fix it. Figured I could post it here so that I have it as a reference and maybe help someone else as well.
There are times when accessing the console for both ESXi and UCS KVM, where you are required to send the F11 key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing PowerShell Core - MacOS</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/installing-powershell-core-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 05:47:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/installing-powershell-core-macos/</guid>
      <description>A thought occurred to me after my last post that there might be users out there that are new to macOS and PowerShell. So to help everyone out, I imagined it might be useful to explain how to install PowerShell on macOS. The task is two parts comprised of first installing Homebrew and then using Homebrew to install PowerShell.
Installing Homebrew Open a terminal window and then run the following command at the prompt:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESXi USB Installer Scripted - Single</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/esxi-usb-installer-scripted-single/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 05:52:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/esxi-usb-installer-scripted-single/</guid>
      <description>In one of my previous posts, I shared the steps to manually configure a USB drive to create an unattended ESXi installation and have it install on itself. The process is not complicated and makes the installation of ESXi much quicker and zero-touch. The manual process of creating USB drives wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t very efficient and did not scale well. To be able to generate more than a few at a time turned out to be time-consuming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESXi USB Installer - Manual</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/esxi-usb-installer-manual/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 05:06:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/esxi-usb-installer-manual/</guid>
      <description>Recently I came across the need to install hundreds of ESXi hosts on USB sticks and wanted to accomplish this in the easiest way possible. While installing ESXi isn&amp;rsquo;t complicated, it can be time-consuming and would require the need to be swapping the monitor and keyboard continually or having multiple monitors and keyboards. I wanted an unattended install method where I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to continue to touch each machine and have to go back configure it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>