<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Datacenter Journey</title>
    <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Datacenter Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 18:54:20 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://datacenterjourney.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First Promotion Computer Operator</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2020/first-promotion-computer-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 18:54:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2020/first-promotion-computer-operator/</guid>
      <description>My first official promotion was not everything that I thought it would be. The position was not very technical; in my opinion, most of the work was operational and related to the AS/400 system. During my training, it became very apparent to me that I would not want to stay in the role very long. However, I did realize that being on the day shift would allow me to make new contacts within the organization and showcase my work ethic and ability to learn quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decommission 6.7 Additional External Platform Services Controller(s) (PSC)</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/decom-external-psc-6.7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:54:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/decom-external-psc-6.7/</guid>
      <description>Back when I deployed my vSphere 6.5 environment in my lab, I wanted to be able to set up Enhanced Link Mode (ELM). To do that, you needed to have an external Platform Services Controller (PSC), but that is no longer the case. Starting in an early version of 6.7, you are now able to connect multiple vCenters in ELM without having to deploy an external PSC. Based on the design recommendations back in 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repoint VCSA to Different PSC</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/repoint-vcsa-to-different-psc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 21:29:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/repoint-vcsa-to-different-psc/</guid>
      <description>To repoint your vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) to a different Platform Services Controller (PSC), you will need to use the cmsso-util repoint command. Using this process is for several different scenarios, including freeing up the capacity load, PSC maintenance, decommissioning a PSC, and various others.
To start, verify what PSC the VCSA is currently pointing to by logging into the VCSA and starting the Bash shell. Then run the command below to check what PSC is currently in use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter 6.5 VAMI Updates Fail with Environment Not Ready</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/vcenter-6.5-vami-updates-fail-with-environment-not-ready/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 19:40:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/vcenter-6.5-vami-updates-fail-with-environment-not-ready/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I mentioned that it had been a while since I had logged into my lab environment, and it was time for some updates. I was running vCenter 6.5u1, and before going to 6.7 wanted to be on the latest release of 6.5. It also allowed me to document the process and share with others who might be inexperienced in how to perform updates from the VCSA (vCenter Server Appliance) VAMI (VMware Appliance Management Interface).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Cmdlet Conflicts</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/powershell-cmdlet-conflicts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 08:39:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/powershell-cmdlet-conflicts/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I had something come up with a client who was migrating from Hyper-V to vSphere. One of the administrators is a big PowerShell user and brought to my attention that the Microsoft Hyper-V and VMware PowerCLI modules share some of the cmdlet names. Duplicate names become an issue when trying to manage particular objects like VMs since both modules have the Get-VM cmdlet. Due to this conflict, he removed the PowerCLI module to continue maintaining the Hyper-V servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send F11 Key on macOS</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/send_f11_on_macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 19:51:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/send_f11_on_macos/</guid>
      <description>I enjoy using a Mac both for work and at home. There is an issue that I have come upon more than one occasion, and it always takes me a while to remember how to fix it. Figured I could post it here so that I have it as a reference and maybe help someone else as well.
There are times when accessing the console for both ESXi and UCS KVM, where you are required to send the F11 key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standalone ESXi Upgrade 6.5 to 6.7u3</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/standalone_esxi_upgrade_6.5_to_6.7u3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 21:33:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/standalone_esxi_upgrade_6.5_to_6.7u3/</guid>
      <description>After logging in to my ESXi host after some time away, I realized that it was still running vSphere 6.5u1. It was time to do an upgrade, and as stated in my last post, I&amp;rsquo;m running a nested lab environment from a single physical host. I am unable to leverage VUM (vCenter Upgrade Manager) to do the upgrades since my vCenter and everything else lives on the one host I need to upgrade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Home Lab</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/my-home-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 21:27:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/my-home-lab/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I had done much with my home lab and decided it was time to give it some much-needed attention. The last update it received was around the time that ESXi 6.5u1 was released. For those of you interested, I am currently running a Supermicro SYS-5028D-TN4T mini-tower running an Intel 8-core Xeon D-1540 processor with 128GB of memory. For network connectivity, it comes with 2x 10GbE and 2x 1GbE ports, and for storage, 4x 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change UCS Fabric Interconnect IPs</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/change-ucs-fi-ips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 20:01:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/change-ucs-fi-ips/</guid>
      <description>It doesn&amp;rsquo;t often happen that you need to change the Management IP Addresses on Cisco UCS Fabric Interconnects once they are configured and placed into production. If you do have to change them for whatever reason, as I have had to in the past, I thought it would be good to post the process and commands here for reference. Make sure you replace any information located within the &amp;lt; &amp;gt; to the IP information of your Fabric Interconnects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Pacific Announcement</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/project-pacific-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 21:10:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/project-pacific-announcement/</guid>
      <description>For those of you that haven&amp;rsquo;t heard VMware made a few big announcements during this year&amp;rsquo;s VMworld US. One of the more interesting to me was the announcement of Project Pacific. In my opinion, this has to be one of the more critical and landscape changing for system administrators and developers. Think of it as the next evolution of vSphere and a step ladder for organizations to be able to implement an application platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First IT Job - Helpdesk</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/first-it-job-helpdesk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 10:01:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/first-it-job-helpdesk/</guid>
      <description>Picking up on my Datacenter Journey from the last post. Now came the thrill of starting to work in the IT field as a Helpdesk technician. Information Systems had been my area of study for the past four and a half years in college. Little did I know that much of what I had learned in school wouldn&amp;rsquo;t benefit me much at the start of my career, but would prove valuable later on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing PowerShell Core - MacOS</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/installing-powershell-core-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 05:47:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/installing-powershell-core-macos/</guid>
      <description>A thought occurred to me after my last post that there might be users out there that are new to macOS and PowerShell. So to help everyone out, I imagined it might be useful to explain how to install PowerShell on macOS. The task is two parts comprised of first installing Homebrew and then using Homebrew to install PowerShell.
Installing Homebrew Open a terminal window and then run the following command at the prompt:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESXi USB Installer Scripted - Single</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/esxi-usb-installer-scripted-single/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 05:52:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/esxi-usb-installer-scripted-single/</guid>
      <description>In one of my previous posts, I shared the steps to manually configure a USB drive to create an unattended ESXi installation and have it install on itself. The process is not complicated and makes the installation of ESXi much quicker and zero-touch. The manual process of creating USB drives wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t very efficient and did not scale well. To be able to generate more than a few at a time turned out to be time-consuming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESXi USB Installer - Manual</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/esxi-usb-installer-manual/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 05:06:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/esxi-usb-installer-manual/</guid>
      <description>Recently I came across the need to install hundreds of ESXi hosts on USB sticks and wanted to accomplish this in the easiest way possible. While installing ESXi isn&amp;rsquo;t complicated, it can be time-consuming and would require the need to be swapping the monitor and keyboard continually or having multiple monitors and keyboards. I wanted an unattended install method where I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to continue to touch each machine and have to go back configure it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey Start</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/journeystart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 17:14:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/journeystart/</guid>
      <description>To give you a little bit of background on me and how I got started in my IT career back in 2002. As a recent college graduate with little to no experience and only armed with a bachelor degree in Management Information Systems, I thought the job offers were going to be plentiful for me to choose from just by applying. Little did I know that it was not as easy as listing the fact that I had a piece a paper showing that I could learn and pass tests.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>