<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VCSA on Datacenter Journey</title>
    <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/categories/vcsa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VCSA on Datacenter Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 20:06:43 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://datacenterjourney.com/categories/vcsa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Install VCSA Certificates MacOS</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2020/install-vcsa-certificates-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 20:06:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2020/install-vcsa-certificates-macos/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve all come across the pesky invalid certificate error when trying to access vCenter, stating that your connection is not private. Many of us click through and &amp;ldquo;Accept the risk&amp;rdquo; because we know that the site we are accessing is legitimate. However, there are times where not having a trusted website can cause an issue and prevent specific actions. For example, without a trusted certificate, it blocks access to upload files to datastores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decommission 6.7 Additional External Platform Services Controller(s) (PSC)</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/decom-external-psc-6.7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:54:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/decom-external-psc-6.7/</guid>
      <description>Back when I deployed my vSphere 6.5 environment in my lab, I wanted to be able to set up Enhanced Link Mode (ELM). To do that, you needed to have an external Platform Services Controller (PSC), but that is no longer the case. Starting in an early version of 6.7, you are now able to connect multiple vCenters in ELM without having to deploy an external PSC. Based on the design recommendations back in 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repoint VCSA to Different PSC</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/repoint-vcsa-to-different-psc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 21:29:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/repoint-vcsa-to-different-psc/</guid>
      <description>To repoint your vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) to a different Platform Services Controller (PSC), you will need to use the cmsso-util repoint command. Using this process is for several different scenarios, including freeing up the capacity load, PSC maintenance, decommissioning a PSC, and various others.
To start, verify what PSC the VCSA is currently pointing to by logging into the VCSA and starting the Bash shell. Then run the command below to check what PSC is currently in use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter 6.5 VAMI Updates Fail with Environment Not Ready</title>
      <link>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/vcenter-6.5-vami-updates-fail-with-environment-not-ready/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 19:40:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datacenterjourney.com/2019/vcenter-6.5-vami-updates-fail-with-environment-not-ready/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I mentioned that it had been a while since I had logged into my lab environment, and it was time for some updates. I was running vCenter 6.5u1, and before going to 6.7 wanted to be on the latest release of 6.5. It also allowed me to document the process and share with others who might be inexperienced in how to perform updates from the VCSA (vCenter Server Appliance) VAMI (VMware Appliance Management Interface).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>